What are some TRT clinic red flags?
>> Hi, and a quick message before we start.
If you appreciate the content we bring
to this channel, consider becoming a
channel member. For the price of a
coffee per month, you will get a loyalty
badge next to your name in the YouTube
comments that will attract your
attention more rapidly and easily when
you have question. Next to many other
perks like membersonly videos, early
access to new videos, rough cuts and
bloopers, and members only live streams.
Use the link under this video to become
a member. Thank you,
>> man. That's a that's going to open a can
of worms for a lot of people. And my red
flag may be different from somebody
else's red flag. I just want people to
know that that I have my own standards
about certain things and what I like to
see. And not everybody those things
don't matter to everybody. So I get
that. I think in general though there
are some things that if you kind of go
through our group, you'll see common red
flags that most people at least in our
group kind of can agree that are red
flags. Um, and it depends on just it
doesn't have to be with a TRT clinic.
There's red flags obviously from if
people want to go through their regular
provider, alipathic provider, whatever,
uh, or osteopathic, any any mainstream
provider if they're trying to do the
insurancebased system. Um, they're going
to probably have a harder time doing
that. Um, most providers are not savvy
to keying in on symptom resolution. They
will still focus primarily on baseline
lab ranges. That's a red flag whether
it's a TRT clinic or a regular clinic or
whatever in my opinion. Um so constant
obsession with labs over the individual
is a red flag. I think throwing people
on multiple compounds at the first visit
is a red flag personally and I know
there are reputable clinics that do that
and they can get away with it in some
people but I've in general I'm I'm a
personally a one variable at a time kind
of guy. um it just makes more sense from
aological perspective just to see what's
affecting the body. So I do if they you
go to a clinic and they're like you need
you know you need to pay us $1,000 for
all these different meds at once because
I've seen it. Um I've seen people
slammed on not only testosterone but
highdose thyroid, DHEA, pregnant alone,
hCG, peptides all in the first visit and
that's a red flag uh to me. Um I think
those are the big ones. Obviously
aromatase inhibitor prescri prescribing
and recommendation of frequent
phbotoies. Both of those are to me are
red flags. Again that's a personal
preference kind of thing. I get it that
some people are passionate about that
topic and they demand they have to
donate or they have to be on an AI. It's
like that's then that's not a red flag
for you. But if you're keyed into the
discussion and what we've talked about
and understand a lot of the the
fallacies involved in those claims when
you do go to those clinics and they
start pushing it, that's a a bit of a
red flag. Now, you can oftentimes give
push back and work work with certain
providers who say, "Oh, no, no, it's
okay. We won't, you know, require that
or you don't have to do the AI. It's
just here if you need it," quote
unquote, which shows me they don't
really know the topic. But, you know,
that's okay. Everybody's got to work
within the bounds of the the clinic and
the finances that they have, you know.
Um, but I would say those are the big
red flags to me. That and I think these
and again, I'm probably stepping on toes
here and and I get it. Um, because we
don't resell medicines or labs, so we
have no dog in that hunt. Um, the
requiring patients to get these massive
lab panels all the time, uh, I think is
a red flag. Um, labs don't tell people
what they think they do. um it's
massively fraught with um philosophical
issues when determining the meaning of
labs, especially baseline labs, not not
it's one thing if you're monitoring a
therapeutic drug level. Um it's another
thing if you're just trying to correlate
a bunch of baselines with people and you
just can't do it. Um but they they get
package deals for these labs and they
push them on people and you know now
that the rise of the functional medicine
world which is kind of drives me nuts.
Um they're claiming they're going to get
to your root cause but it's really just
more and more lab tests. It's like well
then that's not that's not getting the
root cause per se.
>> So just be aware of these kind of
things. I'm not saying these are all
technically red flags but these are
things to look out for. I think um going
like with the insurance route, if you do
try to go the regular dock, that's going
to be hard for you. I can't consider
that a red flag per se, but just know
that you're going to have some hurdles
fighting with insurance companies. And
then doctors who are still in that
insurance model,
you know, they just have a different
mindset in general. Obviously, I didn't
have that mindset when I was doing it
under the insurance model, but I'm I'm
weird, you know, and you'll find some
occasional ones who really enjoy
providing hormones the optimal way and
still have a regular practice. And so
take insurance and I mean those are
diamonds in the rough if you can find
that. Um but I still think in general I
would recommend people not use insurance
uh to get at least not even to pay for
their hormones because you don't want
insurance involved in any any of your
care. You don't want them requiring labs
and and doing I've seen stupid stuff
where they demand the patient be taken
off his testosterone to see if his
levels remain normal or it's just like
no you guys don't get it. So those would
be those would be my big red flags. I'd
say there's probably more. Um, but those
are the big ones that we see most
commonly.